For many of us, online shopping has made the process of purchasing goods a far simpler and more fluid process.
对我们很多人来说，网购让购物的过程变得非常简单顺畅。
No longer do we have to head to the shops to browse and peruse various objects, wandering round endless aisles, before finally settling for the first thing we saw.
我们再也不用专程跑去实体店，在一眼望不到头的货架过道里逛来逛去，仔细翻看琳琅满目的商品，最后却将就买下第一眼看到的东西。
These days, we find the item we want or need online, click on it, and check out its description and user reviews.
如今，我们只需在网上找到想要或需要的商品，点击然后查看商品描述和用户评价。
If it fits the bill, we send it to our basket and pay.
如果它符合要求，就把它加入购物车然后付款。
There seems to be a wealth of options at our fingertips.
似乎海量的选择都触手可及。
But how do we know the options that pop up in front of us really are the best deals.
但我们怎么能确定，眼前跳出来的这些选项真的是最划算的交易呢？
And how might algorithms help or hinder us?
算法在这个过程中，又会起到帮助还是阻碍的作用呢？
Algorithms, simply put, are mathematical instructions which tell the computer how to solve problems.
简单来说，算法就是一系列数学指令，它指导计算机如何解决问题。
When shopping is involved, what is the problem they solve?
那在购物场景里，算法解决的是什么问题呢？
Well, the algorithms instruct the computer which adverts to show and which products a user is most likely to splash the cash on.
其实，算法会指令计算机向用户展示哪些广告，以及哪些商品最有可能让用户掏腰包购买。
By analysing things we’ve previously bought or looked at, the algorithm can predict what goods we’re most likely to be enticed by.
通过分析我们之前购买或浏览过的商品，算法能够预测出我们最有可能被哪些商品吸引。
For some people, the idea of something guessing your preferences could sound a bit intimidating.
对有些人来说，想到有个东西在揣测自己的喜好，可能会觉得有些不安。
But first, let’s look at the positives.
不过我们先来看一看算法的积极作用。
Time is an important thing – something we don’t want to waste too much of.
时间宝贵，我们不愿过多浪费。
By telling the computer to show us adverts for things we are interested in, it can save us a lot of time sifting through things or services that don’t match our criteria.
算法让计算机只给我们推送感兴趣的商品广告，帮我们省去了大量筛选不符合需求的商品或服务的时间。
They can also help us find the best deals.
同时，算法也能帮我们找到最划算的商品。
However, there are some people who have concerns about the impact of algorithms on our shopping experience.
不过，也有一些人担心算法会对我们的购物体验产生负面影响。
It is possible that algorithms may only select options from a limited number of brands, or may favour products from certain companies.
算法有可能只筛选少数品牌的商品供我们选择，或是偏向推送某些特定公司的产品。
There are also concerns that we aren’t always shown the cheapest or best deal, even though that’s what we’re searching for.
还有人担心，即便我们在搜索最实惠的商品，算法也未必会给我们展示最便宜、最划算的选项。
Finally, some algorithms generate ads which tell you there are only a limited number of items you’re interested in left. They might just be there to manipulate you.
最后，有些算法还会生成一些广告，声称你感兴趣的商品库存所剩无几，而这些广告很可能只是为了操纵你下单。
So, the takeaway from this is that algorithms are here to stay, and it’s wise to know they exist.
所以，这件事给我们的启示是，算法的存在已是既定事实，最好清楚这一点。
Whenever you’re shopping, be it online or off, make sure to shop around for the best deals.
无论你是在网上购物还是线下购物，都一定要货比三家，找到最划算的选择。
The first thing you see might not always be the best for you.
你第一眼看到的东西，未必就最适合你。